<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>sophietheopossum@yandex.ru</email>
		<name>Seirra Blake</name>
	</maintainer>
	<use>
		<flag name="amd">Add support for amd cpus</flag>
		<flag name="anaconda">One of your chosen options requires anaconda which has a large number of python development features, you will need to install it from inside sublime text. you can turn off linting with {"anaconda_linting": false}</flag>
		<flag name="archive">install <pkg>app-arch/xarchiver</pkg> in order to access archives with a gui</flag>
		<flag name="ath9k">Install the ath9k driver for 802.11n qualcomm/atheros NICs</flag>
		<flag name="bfq">Install the bfq scheduler</flag>
		<flag name="bmq">Install the bmq scheduler</flag>
		<flag name="broadcom">add support for broadcom devices</flag>
		<flag name="browser">install a graphical web browser</flag>
		<flag name="btrfs">install <pkg>sys-fs/btrfs-progs</pkg> for btrfs, a recently matured snapshotting copy-on-write file system, and the relevant kernel drivers</flag>
		<flag name="bzip2">compress the kernel with bzip2</flag>
		<flag name="cad">install <pkg>media-gfx/solvespace</pkg> for fully parametric 2d and 3d cad that's simple, easy to use and exports to a wide variety of formats</flag>
		<flag name="chrome">install chromium/chrome of some variety</flag>
		<flag name="composite">install <pkg>x11-misc/compton</pkg> to enable compositing, a way to render extra effects and transparency in windows</flag>
		<flag name="composite-gui">install <pkg>lxqt-base/compton-conf</pkg>, a gui to configure compton</flag>
		<flag name="dev">install <pkg>app-portage/repoman</pkg>, a tool designed to aid in managing overlays</flag>
		<flag name="dev-java">install <pkg>dev-util/eclipse-sdk-bin</pkg>, an ide designed for java</flag>
		<flag name="discord">install discord, an online messenger and games store</flag>
		<flag name="efi">ensure efi support is built, most modern systems need this</flag>
		<flag name="ext2">Install drivers to work with ext2 partitions</flag>
		<flag name="exfat">Install drivers to work with exfat partitions</flag>
		<flag name="extended-glyphs">install <pkg>media-fonts/noto</pkg>, a font that supports a lot of glyphs</flag>
		<flag name="f2fs">Install drivers to work with f2fs partitions</flag>
		<flag name="fat">ensure fat filesystem support is built, in many cases this should not be the only filesystem</flag>
		<flag name="firefox">install <pkg>www-client/firefox</pkg>, this is quicker to compile from source, and has better privacy options</flag>
		<flag name="flash">ensure the <pkg>www-plugins/adobe-flash</pkg> plugin is installed. flash is a dying platform, however there are historic games and animations made with it</flag>
		<flag name="fluxbox">use <pkg>x11-wm/fluxbox</pkg> as the window manager of choice. typically this has medium performance and can  even be used as a full desktop solution if so desired</flag>
		<flag name="fslint">install <pkg>app-misc/fslint</pkg>, this is a useful tool for finding duplicate files, empty directories and other such things to help keep a system clean</flag>
		<flag name="ftp">install <pkg>net-ftp/filezilla</pkg> as the ftp client</flag>
		<flag name="fvwm">use <pkg>x11-wm/fvwm</pkg> as the window manager of choice. it has great performance and even has its own desktop environment, however it is very difficult to set up. and is poor at integration.</flag>
		<flag name="gentoo-patches">use the official gentoo patchset</flag>
		<flag name="gentoo-sources">use the official gentoo kernel sources</flag>
		<flag name="gnomekeyring-admin">install <pkg>app-crypt/seahorse</pkg> in order to manage gnome keyring with a gui</flag>
		<flag name="gzip">compress the kernel with gzip</flag>
		<flag name="hygon">Add support for hygon cpus</flag>
		<flag name="index">install mlocate to allow indexing which helps make file searches faster</flag>
		<flag name="inkscape">install <pkg>media-gfx/inkscape</pkg>, a powerful svg and pdf editor</flag>
		<flag name="intel">Add support for intel cpus</flag>
		<flag name="irc">install <pkg>net-irc/kvirc</pkg> in order to use irc. this is often a preferred way to get volunteer support with issues or make quick queries</flag>
		<flag name="ivybridge">Add support for ivybridge cpus</flag>
		<flag name="java-ide">install <pkg>dev-util/eclipse-sdk-bin</pkg>, a popular java ide</flag>
		<flag name="js-lint">Add support for linting javascript in sublime-text using </flag>
		<flag name="kate">install <pkg>kde-apps/kate</pkg> as your gui-based text editor</flag>
		<flag name="kyber">Install the kyber scheduler</flag>
		<flag name="latex">install <pkg>app-office/lyx</pkg>, an editor for latex that's great for beginners</flag>
		<flag name="logisim">install <pkg>sci-electronics/logisim-evolution-holy-cross</pkg>, a fork of a fork of logisom that performs well</flag>
		<flag name="lz4">compress the kernel with lz4</flag>
		<flag name="lzo">compress the kernel with lzo, this usually boots fastest</flag>
		<flag name="mail-client">install <pkg>mail-client/mailspring</pkg>, a partially open source mail client</flag>
		<flag name="mips-emulate">install <pkg>app-emulation/mars-mips</pkg>, a MIPS assembly emulator</flag>
		<flag name="network-tray">install <pkg>gnome-extra/nm-applet</pkg>, a universal system tray that helps with wireless networks</flag>
		<flag name="odt">install <pkg>app-office/libreoffice</pkg> to handle odt files and convert between them</flag>
		<flag name="odt-convert">install <pkg>dev-tex/tex4ht</pkg> to convert latex files to odt, which can subsequently be reviewed and converted to docx with libreoffice</flag>
		<flag name="openbox">use openbox as the window manager of choice. openbox is more widely supported including having its own configuration gui, at the cost of performance</flag>
		<flag name="openrc">Add support for the openrc init system</flag>
		<flag name="overlay">install <pkg>app-portage/layman</pkg> to handle overlays, not using overlays is generally not supported</flag>
		<flag name="parted">install <pkg>sys-block/gparted</pkg> to handle partitions</flag>
		<flag name="pdf-edit">require that the system can edit pdf files</flag>
		<flag name="pdf-view">require that the system can view pdf files</flag>
		<flag name="pdf-view-accurate">install <pkg>app-text/mupdf</pkg> to view high quality pdf renders</flag>
		<flag name="pf-sources">use the pf kernel sources</flag>
		<flag name="php-ide">install <pkg>dev-php/phpstorm</pkg>, a well known non-free php ide</flag>
		<flag name="processviewer">install <pkg>kde-plasma/ksysguard</pkg>, a full gui task manager</flag>
		<flag name="remote-desktop">install <pkg>net-misc/anydesk</pkg> to enable remote desktop functionality</flag>
		<flag name="screenshot">install <pkg>media-gfx/flameshot</pkg> to handle screenshots</flag>
		<flag name="secondlife">install <pkg>games-simulation/firestorm-bin</pkg> as a secondlife viewer</flag>
		<flag name="secure">Various security options that while more secure reduce performance and make things more difficult</flag>
		<flag name="spreadsheet">install <pkg>app-office/gnumeric</pkg> to handle spreadsheets</flag>
		<flag name="sql">install <pkg>dev-db/mariadb</pkg> to handle databases</flag>
		<flag name="steam">install <pkg>games-util/steam-launcher</pkg>, a software distribution platform with one of the largest game catalogues and proton, a built in version of wine</flag>
		<flag name="sublime">install <pkg>app-editors/sublime-text</pkg> as your gui-based text editor. many extra features will require you install plugins, these will require that you install package control. note that sublime text is not free and once you are satisfied in your evaluation of the product you should buy a licence, although you are free to evaluate it as much as required.</flag>
		<flag name="sublimelinter">One of your chosen options requires sublimelinter which is a large linting framework, you will need to install it from inside sublime text</flag>
		<flag name="sudo">install <pkg>app-admin/sudo</pkg> in order to run software as root (admin)</flag>
		<flag name="svg-edit">require that the system can edit svg files</flag>
		<flag name="system-flake8">require that your python linting uses locally installed flake8. you will need to install SublimeLinter-flake8. make sure to disable anaconda linting.</flag>
		<flag name="system-pylint">require that your python linting uses locally installed pylint. you will need to install SublimeLinter-pylint. make sure to disable anaconda linting.</flag>
		<flag name="systemd">Add support for the systemd init system</flag>
		<flag name="terminal">Install <pkg>x11-terms/qterminal</pkg>, a simple terminal emulator often bundled with lxqt</flag>
		<flag name="terminal-fast">install <pkg>x11-terms/kitty</pkg>, a terminal emulator that utilises hardware acceleration to run fast while using theoretically less resources</flag>
		<flag name="text-editor">install a gui based text editor. The default is kate unless you have specific requirements it can't satisfy.</flag>
		<flag name="text-editor-color-highlight">require that your text editor has colour highlighting and thus install <pkg>app-editors/sublime-text</pkg> to satisfy that. you must install Color Highlight to enable it.</flag>
		<flag name="text-editor-js-complete">require that your text editor has javascript code completion and thus install <pkg>app-editors/sublime-text</pkg> to satisfy that. you must install JavaScript Enhancements to enable it as well as the npm package flow.</flag>
		<flag name="text-editor-js-lint">require that your text editor has javascript linting and thus install <pkg>app-editors/sublime-text</pkg> to satisfy that. you must install SublimeLinter contib standard to enable it as well as the npm package standard.</flag>
		<flag name="text-editor-php-lint">require that your text editor has php linting and thus install <pkg>app-editors/sublime-text</pkg> and <pkg>dev-lang/php</pkg> to satisfy that. you must install SublimeLinter-php to enable it.</flag>
		<flag name="text-editor-py-complete">require that your text editor has python code completion and thus install <pkg>app-editors/sublime-text</pkg> to satisfy that.</flag>
		<flag name="threads-4">Add support for a 4 threaded system</flag>
		<flag name="threads-16">Add support for a 16 threaded system</flag>
		<flag name="threads-512">Add support for a 512 threaded system</flag>
		<flag name="uefi">Add support for uefi</flag>
		<flag name="viewfont">use the gui of <pkg>media-gfx/fontforge</pkg> to view all the glyphs a font offers</flag>
		<flag name="xeon">Add support for xeon cpus</flag>
		<flag name="xfs">ensure xfs filesystem support is built, xfs has some of the best performance on kernel 5+ for SSDs</flag>
		<flag name="xz">compress the kernel with xz</flag>
		<flag name="yandex-disk">Install <pkg>net-misc/yandex-disk</pkg>, the official yandex disk client</flag>
		<flag name="zhaoxin">Add support for zhaoxin cpus</flag>
	</use>
</pkgmetadata>
